"The Stranger I Met" Episode 3
'내가 만난 낯선 사람' 3회
(Wu Gang Dumu)
(우강두무)
(Kyung Gi Joo)
(주경기)
"A Stranger I Met"
"내가 만난 낯선 사람"
So this is not an ordinary car but a time travel machine.
그래서 이것은 일반 자동차가 아니라 시간 여행 기계입니다.
Time travel is over there
시간여행은 저기에 있어
I was hit by this car
나 이 차에 치였어
This goes back to 1987 ?
이것은 1987년으로 거슬러 올라갑니다 .
- Cool - Cool, right?
- 멋지다 - 멋지지?
Seeing such a situation, can you still say such a thing?
그런 상황을 보고 도 그런 말을 할 수 있나요?
The car will be repaired anyway
차는 어차피 수리되겠지만
Until then, stay here
그때까지 여기 있어줘
My name is Li Shengyi
내 이름은 리성이입니다.
don't call me mom
나를 엄마라고 부르지 마세요
really scared
정말 무서워
What's your real name?
네 진짜 이름은 뭐니?
My name is Baisu
내 이름은 바이수예요
Are they all girls from your school?
그 사람들이 모두 너희 학교 여자애들이냐?
He fell into the water without saving him
구하지 못한 채 물에 빠졌다
Which friends are watching?
어떤 친구들이 보고 있나요?
Pretend you don't want to see it, sister
보기 싫은 척 누나
one year later
1년 후
I will die at the age of 35
나는 35세에 죽는다
The defendant who killed me was in 1987
나를 죽인 피고인은 1987년생이었습니다.
Because Wu Zongri is the culprit of the serial murders
왜냐면 우종리는 연쇄살인의 범인이니까
This also appeared at the scene of my death
이건 내가 죽는 현장에도 나타났어
This is the defendant's trademark from 1987
이는 피고의 1987년 상표이다.
In any case, it must be sent back before
어쨌든, 그것은 전에 다시 보내져야 합니다
(Bom Bom Theater)
(봄봄극장)
that's why
그렇기 때문에
(Part 3 - The Secret You Have)
(3부 - 당신이 가지고 있는 비밀)
I know
알아요
The era suddenly comes and there is something to do
갑자기 시대가 오면 할 일이 생기고
How illogical and strange
얼마나 비논리적이고 이상합니까?
but
하지만
go out
나가
Because it's colder here than outside
여기가 바깥보다 더 추우니까
First let's go outside
우선 밖으로 나가자
Part (3)
파트(3)
Anyway, I think it will be difficult to go back tonight.
아무튼 오늘 밤에는 돌아가기 어려울 것 같아요.
Get dressed and come out
옷을 입고 나오세요
Are Kimizu and our mother friends?
키미즈와 우리 어머니는 친구인가요?
same class
같은 반
Novel How did it actually happen?
소설 실제로 어떻게 된 일입니까?
Because no one likes me very much
왜냐면 아무도 나를 별로 좋아하지 않거든
that's why
그렇기 때문에
That's why I want to say...
그렇기 때문에 말하고 싶은 것은...
I want to die
나는 죽고 싶다
Mom will have times like this too
엄마도 이런 때가 있을 거에요
never imagined
상상도 못했던
Is that all?
그게 다야?
The mother time I didn’t know
나도 몰랐던 엄마의 시간
I once wanted to be a novelist
나는 한때 소설가가 되고 싶었다.
What kind of content?
어떤 종류의 콘텐츠인가요?
Can you give my mother a signed book?
어머니께 사인된 책을 선물해 주실 수 있나요?
Do not you understand?
이해하지 못합니까?
What books will I read?
어떤 책을 읽을까요?
At the same time, how much do I miss my mom?
동시에 나는 엄마를 얼마나 그리워하는가?
No
아니요
Everything can change here
여기서 모든 것이 바뀔 수 있습니다
(Bom Bom Theater)
(봄봄극장)
How did you know?
어떻게 알았나요?
I think I can't go back now
이제 돌아갈 수 없을 것 같아
There's work to be done here
여기서 해야 할 일이 있어요
What to do there?
거기서 무엇을 해야 하나요?
(Bom Bom Theater)
(봄봄극장)
Do you remember them?
기억하시나요?
5 months and 14 days, 5 months and 16 days, 1987
5개월 14일, 5개월 16일, 1987년
Two women take turns to die
두 여자가 번갈아 가며 죽는다
Then No. 20 disappeared and has not been found yet.
그러다가 20번은 사라져서 아직까지 발견되지 않았습니다.
a woman
여자
Yes, I've seen them all around
네, 주변에서 많이 봤어요
Knowledge
지식
Those who were not killed by you
너한테 죽지 않은 사람들
not really
설마
If those detectives hadn't blamed me then...
그때 그 형사들이 나를 비난하지 않았다면...
I am strong
나는 강하다
Please trust me
제발 날 믿어
Then this
그러면 이
List of main suspects at the time
당시 주요 용의자 명단
There are three people including you
당신 포함 3명이 있어요
Do you remember the other two?
나머지 두 개도 기억하시나요?
Yes, because the community is small
예, 커뮤니티가 작기 때문에
from now on
지금부터
Regarding these six people, including the parties concerned
이들 6명에 대해서는 당사자 포함
tell me everything you remember
당신이 기억하는 모든 것을 말해주세요
Just small is fine
그냥 작아도 괜찮아
I don't know if it's accurate because it has a long memory
기억력이 길기 때문에 정확한지는 모르겠습니다.
Just for reference, don’t worry
참고용이니 걱정하지 마세요
I will introduce it in detail myself
제가 직접 자세히 소개하겠습니다
Because this is a case that doesn't leave much evidence
증거가 많이 남지 않은 사건이기 때문에
That's why it's as close as possible
그렇기 때문에 최대한 가깝게
I will join them and watch
나는 그들과 합류해서 지켜볼 것이다
Every action is monitored
모든 행동이 모니터링됩니다
you have to wait
기다려야합니다
Until shortly before the incident
사건 발생 직전까지
At that time, at least half of these six people were of mixed race.
그 당시 이들 6명 중 적어도 절반은 혼혈이었습니다.
Where do you think it is?
그곳이 어디일 것 같나요?
I'm mixed raceI'm mixed race
나는 혼혈이다나는 혼혈이다
School?
학교?
School
학교
start from there
거기서부터 시작해
I think I have to go to school
학교에 가야 할 것 같아
I have to go to school
나는 학교에 가야 해요
hot pot
뜨거운 냄비
- Hot hot hot - Are you crazy?
- 더워 더워 더워 - 미쳤어?
It's hot
그것은 뜨겁다
(Contact to inquire about spies and communist criminals)
(간첩, 공산범에 대한 문의는 연락주세요)
Do I really have to pay if I get caught?
잡히면 정말 돈을 내야 하나요?
Is it because of meeting a stranger that this happened?
낯선 사람을 만나서 이런 일이 일어난 걸까요?
Everyone I see is weird
내가 보는 사람들은 다 이상해
look at him
그를 봐
- Let's go - Next round
- 가자 - 다음 라운드
- Kyung Hee - Miss
- 경희 - 아가씨
I even know how many hammers and spoons he has in his house
그 사람 집에 망치와 숟가락이 몇 개나 있는지도 알아요
he is hopeless
그 사람은 절망적이야
Do you recognize an unfamiliar face or unfamiliar words?
낯선 얼굴이나 낯선 단어를 인식하시나요 ?
Like coming from a strange other world
마치 낯선 다른 세계에서 온 것 같은
Strange faces, another world
낯선 얼굴, 또 다른 세상
Yes, and where is this place?
네, 그런데 이곳은 어디에 있나요?
People who don’t know what day of the week it is
오늘이 무슨 요일인지 모르는 사람들
- Yeah, I don't know - Well
- 네, 모르겠어요 - 글쎄요
and then
그런 다음
Holding a strange machine and saying strange things
이상한 기계를 들고 이상한 말을 하는 모습
Weird machine...
이상한 기계...
Yesterday I met such a person
어제 그런 사람을 만났어요
Oh, great, I get to see you every day
아, 좋아요, 매일 만나요
I can see clearly because I have good eyes
눈이 좋으니까 또렷하게 볼 수 있어
No
아니요
Who is that?
그 사람은 누구입니까?
Who are you asking?
누구한테 물어보는 거야?
School, do you think this makes sense now?
학교, 이제 이게 말이 된다고 생각하세요?
as a student, not a teacher
선생님이 아닌 학생 으로서
Is there such a terrible thing?
그런 끔찍한 일이 있나요?
I don't even know how hot it is
얼마나 더운지조차 모르겠어
Well, you'll know when you look at it
뭐, 보시면 아시겠지만
if you remove makeup
화장을 지우면
Because the face of the modern era is difficult to predict
현대의 얼굴은 예측하기 어렵기 때문에
If you say you have been out of school for three years
3년 동안 학교를 쉬었다고 하면
completely..
완전히..
You don't have to worry about this
이것에 대해 걱정할 필요가 없습니다
Have you forgotten where this place is?
이곳이 어딘지 잊으셨나요?
Drink slowly while it's hot
뜨거울 때 천천히 마시세요
I will never forget 1987
나는 1987년을 결코 잊지 않을 것이다.
Anyway, I can't go back now
어쨌든 이제 돌아갈 수 없어
It is safe to take a form
양식을 작성하는 것이 안전합니다
I did it over there, so I can do it too, right?
내가 거기서 했으니 나도 할 수 있겠지?
on the other hand
반면에
Don't you think this plan is wrong?
이 계획이 틀렸다고 생각하지 않나요?
What procedures are required? After both parties apply
어떤 절차가 필요합니까? 양측 모두 신청 후
Not that one
그거 말고
Is that why we have to do it here ?
그게 우리가 여기서 해야 하는 이유인가요 ?
So I think it's only right to first explain what it's all about
그러니 먼저 그것이 무엇인지 설명하는 것이 옳다고 생각합니다.
Is anyone coming this time?
이번에는 누군가 오나요?
Is it possible to do this?
이것이 가능합니까?
After all, he is a teacher from Wuzheng Middle School
결국 그는 Wuzheng 중학교의 교사 입니다.
If the chairman knew
회장님이 아셨다면
We are also familiar with the battalion commander
우리는 대대장과 도 잘 알고 있습니다.
What are Badang Badan doing here?
바당바단은 여기서 뭐하고 있나요?
I'll be back soon
곧 돌아올거야
What happened this time
이번에 무슨 일이 있었나요?
Wujiang Municipal Public Security Bureau Serious Case Brigade
우장시 공안국 중대사건대대
Badong Detective No. 8
바동탐정 8호
I'm here to confirm. please wait for a moment
확인하러 왔습니다. 잠시만 기다려주세요
stay
머무르다
I think it needs to be explained what the problem is
문제가 무엇인지 설명해야 할 것 같아요
Do you think it is necessary now?
지금은 필요하다고 생각하시나요?
here
여기
teacher
선생님
Will you call the chairman?
회장님한테 전화할래?
That guy is always talking nonsense on a moonlit night
그 사람은 달밤에 맨날 헛소리만 하네
Mazuto
진렬한 사람
Let's register
등록하자
Carefully this time
이번엔 조심히
- Shin - Didn't you hear?
- 신 - 못 들었어?
I'm here because I got a complaint about a stranger
낯선 사람에 대한 불만이 있어서 왔습니다
Register
등록하다
Disappeared once before
예전에 한 번 사라졌어요
If you don't even make that much effort
그렇게 노력하지도 않으면
I don't think there's any other way to prove who you are
당신이 누구인지 증명할 수 있는 다른 방법은 없다고 생각해요
I know
알아요
let's go
갑시다
Wait, police station?
잠깐, 경찰서요?
- Come on - Police station?
- 어서 - 경찰서요?
-Wait a moment
- 잠깐만 요
Are you crazy?
제정신이에요?
Are you doing this because you trust the chairman?
회장님을 믿기 때문에 이러는 겁니까?
to show action
액션을 보여주다
I know you are so passionate
나는 당신이 매우 열정적이라는 것을 알고 있습니다
I helped because I was worried that I would suffer in vain.
제가 헛되이 고생할까봐 걱정해서 도와줬어요.
this is a waste of time
이건 시간 낭비야
Have accurate information and a way to prove it
정확한 정보와 이를 증명할 수 있는 방법이 있어야 합니다.
You can verify it yourself if you wish
원하시면 직접 확인하셔도 됩니다
Have specific information
구체적인 정보가 있음
Yes
예
This kid...
이 아이...
Wuzheng Middle School senior students
우정중학교 선배들
Ross
로스
-Is it really big? -certainly
- 정말 크죠? -틀림없이
OK
좋아요
-Hi
-안녕하세요
oh
오
What year were you born? Aw 1965
몇년도에 태어 났습니까? 아 1965년
May 15, 1965
1965년 5월 15일
Good morning sir
안녕하세요 선생님
Well, hello, Miss Sun
그럼 안녕, 미스 선
- Hello - Mitsu?
- 안녕 - 미즈?
- I'm a lady - Cool, yes.
- 저는 여자예요 - 그렇군요.
I'm really grateful for this
정말 고마워요
What should I do after my registration number is 63?
등록번호가 63이 된 후에는 어떻게 해야 하나요?
I will take a short break
잠시 쉬겠습니다
come over
이리와
Why ?
왜 ?
- Come here, wait a minute. - What is this place?
- 이리 와봐, 잠깐만 - 여긴 뭐지?
Why is this a toy store?
여기가 왜 장난감 가게인가요?
Now I know how dangerous it is
이제 그게 얼마나 위험한지 알아요
If something goes wrong, you and me
무슨 일이라도 생기면 너와 나
It ends awkwardly here
여기서 어색하게 끝나네
I know
알아요
I saw and felt it yesterday
어제 보고 ​​느꼈어요
I will go to school to avoid making mistakes
나는 실수하지 않기 위해 학교에 갈 것이다
Be sure to say the word
꼭 말을 하세요.
I went because I had something to do
할 일이 있어서 갔어요
Because this is a dangerous situation
위험한 상황이니까
The lake has been prepared for a long time
호수는 오랫동안 준비되어 있었습니다
Get ready for the pool..Use words like this
수영장에 갈 준비를 하세요..이런 단어를 사용하세요
Be careful
조심하세요
I know, I'm sorry, I'll be careful
알겠습니다 미안해요 조심할게요
Because this is the first trip
이번 여행이 처음이니까
that's why
그렇기 때문에
The first person to travel through time. What were you doing in school?
최초로 시간여행을 한 사람, 학교에서는 무엇을 하고 있었나요?
There must be a reason
이유가 있을 거에요
Do you think you don’t know enough?
당신이 충분히 모른다고 생각합니까?
A person who can travel freely through time and space
시간과 공간을 자유롭게 여행할 수 있는 사람
Another time, I bought a house
또 한번은 집을 샀어요
Pretend to be an ordinary teacher
평범한 선생님인 척
Travel to and from the office as usual
평소처럼 사무실을 오가며 이동하세요.
To and from the office
사무실 왕복
worst thing in life
인생에서 최악의 일
Such a dangerous and dangerous lie
너무 위험하고 위험한 거짓말
enough to think
생각할 만큼
It must be for important personal reasons
중요한 개인적인 이유가 있을 것입니다.
But I don't ask why
하지만 이유는 묻지 않아요
If you don’t have the confidence to speak up, don’t ask.
말할 자신이 없다면 묻지 마세요.
correct answer
정답
let's do what we have to do first
먼저 해야 할 일부터 하자
Instead, let’s not encounter difficult situations like yesterday
대신 어제처럼 어려운 상황은 겪지 말자
I will try
나는 노력할 것이다
until we come back
우리가 돌아올 때까지
Because they are in the same boat
같은 배를 타고 있기 때문에
I have to go to school
나는 학교에 가야 해요
Return to China after graduation
졸업 후 중국으로 귀국
Be as inconspicuous as possible
최대한 눈에 띄지 않게 하세요
if it interferes with my case
내 사건에 방해가 된다면
At that time, school was over
그땐 학교가 끝났어
This is true no matter what time
이건 언제가 되든 마찬가지야
I agree
나는 동의한다
But I don’t know if the detective yesterday will come again.
그런데 어제 형사가 또 올지 는 모르겠어요 .
i don't know how to speak
나는 어떻게 말하는지 모르겠어요
Let's go first
먼저 가자
let's go
갑시다
Yes Yes
예 예
What are you afraid of?
당신은 무엇을 두려워합니까?
Don't worry
괜찮아요
It is also possible for young people to work part-time
청년 도 파트타임으로 일할 수 있다
Come back quickly and buy a bottle of rice wine
빨리 돌아와서 막걸리 한 병 사오세요
The only son was sent to a distant place
외아들은 먼 곳으로 보내졌다
Think of your lonely friend
외로운 친구를 생각해 보세요
Cool, I know, hang up, Commander Gin.
알겠습니다. 끊으세요, 진 사령관님.
(Principal Yoon Bong-koo)
(윤봉구 교장)
sorry
죄송합니다
My call is a bit long
통화가 좀 깁니다
Now
지금
I am really happy today
오늘 정말 행복해요
This is my first time moving to a new school since school started
개학 이후 처음 으로 새 학교로 전학을 갑니다.
even two
두 개라도
This is also within one day
이것도 하루만에
There is another picture
또 다른 사진이 있어요
- I don't wear it
- 안 입어요
Although I briefly met him in a club not too long ago
얼마 전 클럽에서 잠깐 만났지만
say goodbye officially
공식적으로 작별 인사를 해라
I am Mr. Yoon Hye-jun
저는 윤혜준 씨입니다
if you look carefully
주의깊게 보면
- Picture.. - I don't wear it
- 사진.. - 안 입어요
Yes
예
Anyway
그래도
From today on, this is your nephew's class teacher.
오늘부터 이 사람이 네 조카의 담임이다.
Is the father the same person?
아버지도 같은 사람인가요?
so me too
나도 그래
I need it
나는 그것이 필요하다
Detective Badong is a very good detective
바동형사님 은 정말 좋은 탐정이에요
Thanks to these children, our village
이 아이들 덕분에 우리 마을은
very safe
매우 안전
I have to think of it as gratitude
감사하다고 생각해야겠어요
i absolutely need it
나한테 꼭 필요해
How could I meet such a nice person last night?
어젯밤에 어떻게 이렇게 좋은 사람을 만날 수 있었을까?
Oh, sorry, Chairman
아 죄송해요 회장님
No, I didn't know it was a member of our family
아니요, 우리 가족인지는 몰랐어요
Because the head teacher and parents of students
왜냐하면 교장 선생님과 학생들의 부모님들이
We are all part of the Wuzheng Middle School family
우리는 모두 Wuzheng 중학교 가족 의 일원 입니다
Let's get comfortable, okay?
편하게 지내자, 응?
second head
두 번째 머리
The first head is here too
첫 번째 머리도 여기에 있습니다
What a mystery
정말 미스터리네요
Uncle Yang, I see these two heads here
양삼촌, 여기 머리 두 개가 보여요
as far as I know
내가 아는 한
It seems you don't have a father either
너도 아버지가 없는 것 같구나
not talking
말하지 않고
What happened again?
또 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
Even though he moved to a new school
새로운 학교로 전학을 갔음에도 불구하고
If you come with distant relatives
먼 친척들과 함께 오신다면
The answer is obvious
답은 뻔하다
Even if there are still people who won’t come
아직도 안 오는 사람이 있어도
elementary, middle, and high school
초, 중, 고등학교
Welcome ceremony graduation sports meeting
환영식 졸업 체육대회
Such a person has never been here for a day
그런 사람은 하루도 여기에 온 적이 없습니다
After drinking, he started fighting with someone by the collar.
술을 마신 후 그는 누군가와 멱살을 잡고 싸우기 시작했습니다.
Such a person has gone through all the important moments in my life
그런 사람은 내 인생의 중요한 순간을 모두 겪었습니다
My father is such a person
우리 아버지는 그런 분이시다
Is there such a father?
그런 아버지가 있나요?
bamboo
대나무
It feels strange to hear these words from your mouth
네 입에서 그런 말을 들으면 기분이 이상해
So what's the main thing?
그렇다면 가장 중요한 것은 무엇입니까?
preschool
취학 전의
School name must be Primary School
학교 이름은 초등학교 여야 합니다.
So if you come here to support me
그러니 나를 지지하러 여기로 오신다면
Ekantasun E also...
에칸타순 E도...
hehe
헤헤
Did I tell you yesterday?
내가 어제 말했지?
- Not interested - Wait a minute
- 관심 없음 - 잠깐만요
hehe
헤헤
I also said it yesterday
어제도 말했지
Don't meddle in my business
내 일에 간섭하지 마세요
open my ears
내 귀를 열어라
(teacher's office)
(교무실)
Not like distant relatives
먼 친척 같지도 않고
Didn't I say it's cool?
내가 멋지다고 말하지 않았나요?
Yes, although I promise to keep it that way
응, 그래도 그렇게 하기로 약속하지만
- So cute - No, he's the coolest
- 너무 귀여워 - 아니, 그 사람이 제일 멋있어
- Haha- He bought it
- 하하- 그 사람이 샀어요
- Hey, I don't have any pocket money. - Let me do it.
- 야, 나 용돈 없어 - 내가 해볼게.
- That's right - not these girls.
- 맞아요 - 이 여자들은 아니예요.
- Hey, do you have any left? - No, give me one.
- 야, 남은 거 있어? - 아니, 하나 주세요.
(Employment Studies)
(취업 연구)
- is that so? - Yes
- 그렇습니까? - 예
bamboo
대나무
- Oh - Madam
- 아 - 부인
- How are you ?
- 어떻게 지내세요 ?
Mother
어머니
hehe
헤헤
monitor
감시 장치
goodbye
안녕히 가세요
- Hello
- 안녕하세요
Come in
올
(Five Flavors Award)
(다섯가지 맛상)
This is the same lesson we started teaching today
이것은 오늘 우리가 가르치기 시작한 것과 같은 수업입니다
Pei Yunying
페이 윤잉
I missed a little school because of housework
집안일 때문에 학교에 조금 빠졌어요
a little older than you
너보다 조금 나이가 많아
What does it have to do with old age?
노년과 무슨 관련이 있나요?
If you are in the same class, you are all friends
같은 반이면 다 친구
- That's right - Yes
- 그렇죠 - 예
Cool, check it out yourself
좋아요, 직접 확인해 보세요
not yet
아직 아님
Geun Hye Kyung Lee Eun Ha Bayuri
이근혜경 이은하 바유리
You three, Ginglieburt, are barely moving.
너희 셋, Ginglieburt는 거의 움직이지 않고 있다.
If you bully a new classmate, you will be punished
새로운 반 친구를 괴롭히면 벌을 받습니다
Yes
예
The same goes for upper-class seniors
상류층도 마찬가지다.
There is indeed no hope
정말 희망이 없습니다
Except our Mitsu
우리 미츠만 빼고
(Five Flavors Award)
(다섯가지 맛상)
There's an empty seat there. Go sit down.
거기 빈자리 있으니 가서 앉으세요
Yes
예
That's it
그게 다야
- thanks, thanks
- 감사 감사
come over
이리와
- Ha - Hey
- 하 - 야
- Don't do this. - Really?
- 이러지 마세요 - 정말요?
- Are you kidding me? - Very good.
- 지금 장난하시나요? - 아주 좋아요.
- That's what I can do - Hey, the teacher is here
- 그게 내가 할 수 있는 일이야 - 야, 선생님이 오셨어
- You - bring it back.
- 당신 - 다시 가져오세요.
Quiet
조용한
I have a seat
자리가 있어요
Now there is a new student in our class
이제 우리 반에 새로운 학생이 왔습니다
Feel free to say goodbye
자유롭게 작별 인사를 하세요.
This is Bashisu
바시스입니다
What have you done?
당신은 무엇을 했나요?
Yes
예
Said a lot
많이 말했어
Because it goes against the spirit of rock and roll
로큰롤 정신에 어긋나기 때문에
- Okay - See?
- 알았어 - 봤어?
Excellent
훌륭한
Yes, that's how the pattern is set up
응, 패턴이 그렇게 정해져 있는 거야
What will happen if we go against the spirit?
우리가 영에 어긋나면 어떻게 될까요?
sit where you like
좋아하는 곳에 앉아
That's it
그게 다야
smoothly
순조롭게
- smoothly
- 원활하게
How did it happen?
어떻게이 일이 일어 났어요?
I think I should stay here a little longer
내 생각엔 여기 좀 더 있어야 할 것 같아
are you happy?
행복하니?
Do you like Virginia Wolfe?
버지니아 울프를 좋아하시나요?
Do you know this book?
이 책을 아시나요?
"If you give her a hundred years."
"그녀에게 백년을 준다면."
"Give her her own room."
"그녀에게 자신의 방을 주세요."
"If you give me 500 days a year"
"나에게 1년 500일을 준다면"
"Let her speak her mind."
"그녀가 자신의 생각을 말하게 해주세요."
“If only half of what I’m using now could be removed.”
"지금 사용하는 것의 절반만 제거할 수 있다면."
"I concluded that I could write a better book. "
"나는 더 나은 책을 쓸 수 있다는 결론을 내렸습니다."
"If you give me another hundred years, she will."
"나에게 100년을 더 준다면 그녀는 그렇게 할 것입니다."
"I want to be a poet"
"나는 시인이 되고 싶어요"
They are bathing the cat
그들은 고양이를 목욕시키고 있다
(Employment Studies)
(취업 연구)
I am very happy
나는 매우 행복하다
(Commitment Letter of Diligence and Integrity)
(근면과 성실의 서약서)
bamboo
대나무
you can really play guitar
너 정말 기타를 칠 수 있구나
Hear that?
그거 들었어?
Slater ranked fourth
슬레이터는 4위를 차지했습니다.
Are you playing with electronic codes?
전자 코드를 가지고 놀고 있나요?
Bamboo fingers are also very fast and have a good sense of rhythm
대나무 손가락도 매우 빠르고 리듬감도 좋습니다.
I finally found my partner
드디어 내 파트너를 찾았어요
I am very happy
나는 매우 행복하다
My name is Yu Bum
내 이름은 유범이에요
Aren't you crazy?
미친거 아냐?
I am very happy
나는 매우 행복하다
Said he was very happy
매우 행복하다고 하더군요
I have to say something, don't I?
뭔가 말해야 할 것 같아요, 그렇죠?
but in a decidedly childish way
하지만 확실히 유치한 방식으로
Because they are all childish jokes
다 유치한 장난이니까
What will it be?
그것은 무엇입니까?
I don’t know if it’s a good use or not.
좋은 활용인지 아닌지는 모르겠습니다.
- Already following - Yes
- 이미 팔로우하고 있음 - 예
This Bakola
이 바콜라
I am excited
나는 흥분된다
teacher
선생님
I must speak for a while
잠시 얘기 좀 해야겠어
Where are you pretending to be kissing? Do you want to die?
어디서 키스하는 척 죽고 싶어?
Because I don’t have time, I listen carefully
시간이 없으니까 잘 들어요
Now the other person’s eyes
이제는 상대방의 눈
look at this
이거 봐요
almost
거의
And then all of a sudden, what was that?
그러다가 갑자기 그게 뭐였지?
Well, that's a nod.
글쎄요, 고개를 끄덕이는군요.
Just then he sat down to pack his things
바로 그 순간 그는 짐을 싸기 위해 자리에 앉았습니다.
raise your head like this
이렇게 고개를 들어
I had a nosebleed once...
코피를 흘린 적이 있었는데..
Hey you won't do this again
야 너 다시는 이러지 않을 거야
Now that I think about it I'm doing this
지금 생각해보면 난 이걸 하고 있는 중이야
I'll bow like this
이렇게 절하겠습니다
Is the head made of stone?
머리가 돌로 되어있나요?
That's why you teach
그렇기 때문에 가르치는 거죠.
ha
하아
Our father taught us this
우리 아버지는 우리에게 이것을 가르쳐 주셨습니다.
when i started preschool
내가 유치원을 시작했을 때
If the first child you meet is aggressive
처음 만나는 아이가 공격적이라면
I told him he did it to scare me
나는 그에게 겁을 주려고 그랬다고 말했어요.
Although my parents passed away when I graduated, I am no longer with them
제가 졸업할 때 부모님이 돌아가셨지만 저는 더 이상 부모님과 함께 있지 않습니다.
Although I have never learned anything other than this
비록 이것 외에는 배운 적이 없지만
but because it's still useful
하지만 여전히 유용하기 때문에
Dads want to teach techniques like this
아빠들은 이런 기술을 가르쳐주고 싶어
that's why
그렇기 때문에
Does your father want to run away?
아버지가 도망가고 싶어하시나요?
There must be a reason
이유가 있을 거에요
- You know what - Yeah
- 그거 알아요 - 응
A 19-year-old boy is teaching children
19세 소년이 아이들을 가르치고 있다
There's no need for that
그럴 필요는 없어
ha
하아
How are you?
어떻게 지내세요?
- My nose is bleeding. - Ha.
- 코피가 나네요 - 하하.
Are you crazy?
제정신이에요?
Please be quiet
조용히 해주세요
I can't concentrate anymore
더 이상 집중할 수가 없어요
I think that's enough
그 정도면 충분하다고 생각해요
ha
하아
Prince No. 52 is here
52호 왕자가 왔습니다
What
무엇
- Attention - Sit down
- 주의 - 앉으세요
fish
물고기
Four
4개
- What happened? - Shu
- 무슨 일이에요? - 슈
Now I have to enjoy this moment as much as possible
이제 이 순간을 최대한 즐겨야지
three
삼
Year
년도
one
하나
What were you told to do after graduation?
졸업 후에는 무엇을 하라고 말씀하셨나요?
- I have to go home
- 집에 가야 해요
Yes, I have to go back and do my homework.
응, 돌아가서 숙제를 해야 해.
Don't go out after ten o'clock in the evening
저녁 10시 이후에는 나가지 마세요
I can't go to the reading room because I have to go to work
일을 해야 해서 독서실에 갈 수가 없어요.
Studying at home this time
이번에는 집에서 공부해요
If you can't concentrate, sleep like this
집중이 안되면 이렇게 자세요
Sleep is the best medicine
잠은 최고의 보약이다
Don’t go to the mountains or riverside during the day
낮에는 산이나 강변에 가지 마세요.
Don't go to the dentist
치과에 가지 마세요
Don't go to dark places
어두운 곳에 가지 마세요
Don't trust anyone easily
누구도 쉽게 믿지 마세요
The bad guy comes with a smile
나쁜 놈은 웃으며 다가온다
Currently, my school friends
요즘 학교 친구들이
think about it
그것에 대해 생각해보세요
Wait three or four months until you are 20
20살이 될 때까지 3~4개월을 기다리세요
I'm free from now on
난 이제부터 자유야
- So... - Let's study this time, teacher.
- 그럼... - 이번에는 공부합시다, 선생님.
open book
책 공개 시험
before that rant
그 호언장담 전에
just a fish
그냥 물고기야
The five-second prince because he is the five-second prince
5초왕자는 5초왕자 니까.
Nickname of Prince Wuer
우어 왕자의 별명
Unless you don't listen, do you have to listen every time?
듣지 않는 이상 매번 들어야 하나요?
so terrible
너무 끔찍해
don't just say too much
너무 많은 말만 하지 마세요
It is also known as Dom Prince
돔 프린스라고도 알려져 있어요
don't tell me
나에게 말하지 마세요
So why does every name have to include prince?
그렇다면 왜 모든 이름에 Prince가 포함되어야 할까요 ?
How could I not add it?
어떻게 추가하지 않을 수 있나요?
To write Yunbe Ochunga
윤베 오춘가를 쓰다
Learn how to use it
사용 방법 알아보기
Features that are different from Yoongi Ochunga
윤기오춘가와 다른점
the form described
설명된 형태
must understand
이해해야 한다
Now first
이제 먼저
Let’s talk about Yunbi Ochung’s net worth
윤비오청 순자산에 대해 이야기해보겠습니다.
as i said yesterday
내가 어제 말했듯이
First written in our words by Yonbe Ochunga
우리 말로 처음 쓴 욘베 오춘가
a long poem
긴 시
Because it is reflected in music and literature
음악이나 문학에 반영되기 때문에
Korean literature is valuable
한국문학은 가치가 있다
This work is from the late Goryeo Dynasty
이 작품은 고려 말기의 작품이다.
In studying the early Korean language
초기 한국어를 공부하면서
Has historical value..
역사적 가치가 있는..
- Hello sir
- 안녕하세요 선생님
Mom...Grandpa hates me
엄마...할아버지는 나를 싫어해요
I hate people who fight too
나도 싸우는 사람이 싫어
I said so much because I am calm
너무 차분해서 그런 말을 했어
I've been losing UFC fights since day one
나는 UFC 경기 첫날부터 지고 있었다
Let’s do our own thing and don’t criticize each other
우리 할 일만 하고 서로 비난하지 말자
that's what i said
그게 내가 말한거야
Don’t look too closely during class
수업시간에 너무 자세히 보지 마세요
You can't go anywhere after graduation.
졸업 후에는 아무데도 갈 수 없습니다.
Stay in the classroom because I'm going to call you
내가 전화할 테니까 교실에 있어.
- Teacher - Yes
- 선생님 - 예
go where you have to go
가야 할 곳으로 가라
Wow
우와
Do you talk very intimately?
아주 친밀하게 이야기하나요?
Thank you so much
매우 감사합니다
Thank you for your compliments on your homework
숙제에 대해 칭찬해주셔서 감사합니다
I say well written because it is well written
잘 썼기 때문에 잘 썼다고 한다
It's not a matter of gratitude
감사할 일이 아니다
This time I was a little shy to show it
이번엔 보여주기가 좀 쑥스러워서
In fact, I later
사실 저는 나중에
Do you think you could be a novelist?
소설가가 될 수 있다고 생각하시나요?
certainly
틀림없이
Even if it takes too long, it will take too long
너무 오래 걸려도 너무 오래 걸릴 거예요
I don’t know if it will be very popular.
큰 인기를 끌지는 모르겠습니다.
so work hard
그러니 열심히 일해라
Do you know Jimmy Zu?
지미 주(Jimmy Zu)를 아시나요?
This is a best-selling author
베스트셀러 작가입니다
(academic points)
(학점)
Not in the bathroom either
화장실에도 없고
Where will it go?
어디로 갈까요?
Did you bring it?
가져왔어?
Excellent
훌륭한
I fixed some existing sentences
기존 문장 일부를 수정했습니다.
The content is also fixed
내용도 정해져 있어요
You are already tired from doing homework
숙제하느라 벌써 피곤하다
but
하지만
Almost all the lines I wrote were deleted
제가 쓴 글은 거의 다 삭제됐어요
Oh, that's it
아, 바로 그거야
It doesn't matter
그것은 중요하지 않습니다
Because that will be a good result
그러면 좋은 결과가 있을 테니까
Anyway, I wrote the original work
아무튼 제가 원작을 썼어요
The thing is, anyone can do it
문제는 누구나 할 수 있다는 것
Isn't it?
그렇지 않나요?
Well, yes, of course
응, 물론이지
So come out quickly
그러니까 빨리 나와라
Excellent
훌륭한
Because good results come from your hands
좋은 결과는 당신의 손에서 나오니까
I have no general complaints
나는 일반적인 불만이 없습니다
Corrected
수정됨
anyone can do it
누구나 할 수 있다
(Storage Room)
(창고)
(Always pay attention to fire prevention)
(항상 화재 예방에 주의하세요)
I've always done this
난 항상 이렇게 해왔어
I wonder if it's the same for you
당신도 마찬가지일까 궁금해요
Can you write without help ?
도움 없이 글을 쓸 수 있나요?
Although I have watched it for six years
6년 동안 지켜봤지만
Even if it’s just a little homework
작은 숙제라도
I'm surprised others hired and got it done
다른 사람들이 고용해서 일을 해낸 것에 놀랐습니다.
If you really think anyone can do it
정말로 누구나 할 수 있다고 생각한다면
Why do you have to do it yourself?
왜 직접 해야 하나요?
Leverage other people's skills
다른 사람의 기술을 활용하라
Are you that bald?
당신은 대머리인가요?
No, not bald
아니요, 대머리는 아닙니다
I think it's embarrassing
부끄러운 것 같아요
Hiding in this place?
이런 곳에 숨어 있나요?
Such a thing
그런 것
At least here, it can't be a secret
적어도 여기서는 비밀이 될 수 없어
Let's go to the teacher's office
선생님 사무실로 가자
Misu, are you okay?
미수야, 괜찮아?
this..
이것..
I want to do it
나 그거하고 싶어
Class is about to start, come on
수업이 곧 시작되니까 어서
Let's go to Mizu
미즈로 가자
how to really do it
진짜 어떻게 해야하지?
Why can't my mother move like this?
엄마는 왜 이렇게 움직이지 못하는 걸까요?
There must be something there
거기엔 뭔가가 있을 텐데
This is the first face I've ever seen
이런 얼굴은 처음 본다
A room in the upper class?
상류층의 방?
Is Lee Sun-el in your room?
이선엘씨 방에 계세요?
Sun El Sun El Why?
순엘순엘 왜요?
he..
그..
Can you give me this?
이것을 나에게 줄 수 있습니까?
I trust you
나는 당신을 신뢰합니다
Now you know how fishy this is
이제 이게 얼마나 수상한 일인지 아시겠죠?
Go to the corridor where the girls' classroom is
여자 교실이 있는 복도로 가세요
Don’t you know not to cut it?
자르면 안되는 거 모르시나요?
Are school rules a joke?
학교 규칙이 장난인가요?
no i'm sorry
아냐 미안해
- Please forgive me once - Come on
- 한 번만 용서해주세요 - 자
(Copyrighted invention)
(저작권이 있는 발명품)
(Let us move forward with wisdom)
(지혜롭게 앞으로 나아가자)
- Did you come back? - Tarta
- 돌아왔나요? - 타르타
If Wumisu is really as far away as the novels written by my mother
우미수가 정말 우리 엄마가 쓴 소설만큼 멀리 있다면
Today's question is just the beginning
오늘의 질문은 시작에 불과합니다
I can't even sleep because it makes me feel so uncomfortable
너무 불편해서 잠도 못 자요
(Let us give up ourselves and love each other)
(우리 자신을 포기하고 서로 사랑하자)
Why is it taking so long?
왜 이렇게 오래 걸리나요?
don't go anywhere and wait
아무데도 가지 말고 기다리세요
Be careful
조심하세요
What
무엇
Yun Yang, be careful
윤양아, 조심해
Do you really want to go to this place?
정말 이 곳으로 가고 싶나요?
The principal said today's dinner was really...
교장선생님께서 오늘 저녁은 정말...
Even if it rains, the earth will split in two
비가 와도 지구는 반으로 갈라진다
I was told I had to attend
참석해야 한다고 들었습니다
I've been talking a lot since before
예전부터 말을 많이 했었는데
so?
그래서?
How much do you know about the principal who has just been here a month?
이제 막 이곳에 온 지 한 달이 된 교장 선생님에 대해 얼마나 알고 있나요 ?
so
그래서
Why would the principal fall in love with such a person?
교장은 왜 그런 사람을 사랑하게 될까요?
Sorry, I'm late
미안 늦었 어
No?
아니요?
What
무엇
Are you not as smart as I thought?
당신은 내가 생각한 것만큼 똑똑하지 않은가?
being threatened
위협을 받고 있다
Horrible people to work with
같이 일하기 무서운 사람들
that warning
그 경고
Until now, I don’t know how Shan’e was restrained, but I listened carefully
지금까지 Shan'e가 어떻게 제지했는지는 모르겠지만 잘 들었습니다.
What you have done so far
지금까지 무엇을 했는지
All the cowardly things he did to get ahead
그가 앞서기 위해 했던 모든 비겁한 짓들
It won't be what you want anymore
더 이상 당신이 원하는 것은 아닐 거예요
I will stop everything no matter what
무슨 일이 있어도 다 멈출 거야
Yes
예
Misu
미스
Where are you going?
어디 가세요?
A chapter from the senior year to the freshmen
고학년부터 신입생까지의 한 장
Let's see what we do here
여기서 우리가 무엇을 하는지 봅시다
Mom told me to come back early
엄마가 일찍 오라고 했어
I have a place where I can go in for a while, but I’m going back today
잠시 들어갈 수 있는 곳이 있는데 오늘은 돌아갈게요
He Wuguang
허 우광
Do you think my sister ran away like this?
내 여동생이 이렇게 도망갔을 것 같아?
No eavesdropping allowed
도청은 허용되지 않습니다
When the windows are opened due to cloudy weather
흐린 날씨로 인해 창문을 열었을 때
So even if it hurts
그러니 아파도
I don't know anything about Mitsu's method
나는 미츠의 ​​방법에 대해 아무것도 모른다
if you want to fight
싸우고 싶다면
Shouldn't you be sure of the other person's situation ?
상대방의 상황을 확실히 알아야 하지 않겠습니까 ?
Which way do you want to go?
어느 쪽으로 가고 싶나요?
Then give it to new classmates
그런 다음 새로운 반 친구들에게 주세요.
I want to write a message
메시지를 쓰고 싶어요
Hey, do you have a girlfriend?
아, 여자친구 있어요?
Hey, people change all the time, you know?
야, 사람은 맨날 변하는 거 알지?
if i see a beautiful girl
내가 아름다운 여자를 본다면
Brave girlfriend first...
용감한 여자친구 먼저...
I just gave
방금 줬어요
I tried it first
제가 먼저 시도해 봤는데
A guy who can't even lift weights
역기조차 못 드는 남자
I just need to ask for the phone number
전화번호만 물어보면 돼요
It would be fine if the head teacher didn't stop me
교장 선생님이 말리지 않으면 괜찮을 텐데.
Well
잘
I'll go find the head teacher tomorrow
내일 교장 선생님을 찾으러 갈게요
- cool guy
- 쿨 가이
"What's your home phone number?"
"집 전화번호가 몇 번이에요?"
Yes 53 2355
예 53 2355
What 53 2355
뭐 53 2355
i heard somewhere
어디선가 들었어
Hey, isn't this the head teacher's phone number?
야 이거 교장선생님 전화번호 아니야?
Well, our new student
자, 우리 신입생
If you remember, give me a call and I'll take care of it
생각나시면 전화주시면 처리해드리겠습니다
Come back soon
곧 돌아와
(Let's use it as a private toilet)
(개인 화장실로 사용하자)
How to do it?
어떻게 하나요?
I don't think so, but it won't be an umbrella
그럴 것 같지는 않지만 우산은 아닐 것 같아요
As a student, can I say whatever I want?
학생으로서 하고 싶은 말은 무엇이든 할 수 있나요?
I am 22 years old
나는 22 살이다
oh yes
바로 이거 야
So, what does this word mean?
그렇다면 이 단어는 무엇을 의미하는가?
I know very little about the Five Lights Dharma
나는 오광법에 대해 아는 바가 거의 없습니다.
I said I was threatened
협박을 당했다고 말했어요
If you really feel this way
정말 이런 느낌이라면
Probably not a real threat
아마도 실제 위협은 아닐 것입니다.
This is a casual test
이건 캐쥬얼한 테스트인데
Is this a test?
이게 테스트인가요?
Is there such a thing?
그런 게 있나요?
Which button does it respond to when pressed?
어떤 버튼을 누르면 반응합니까?
What are the disadvantages?
단점은 무엇입니까?
Is there something as useful as a secret card?
비밀 카드만큼 유용한 것이 있나요?
Mizu didn't attack at all until she fully understood this
미즈는 이 사실을 완전히 이해할 때까지 전혀 공격하지 않았습니다.
but if you know
하지만 당신이 알고 있다면
it's over
끝났어
threaten..
위협하다..
Horrible people to work with
같이 일하기 무서운 사람들
Yes
예
Be careful
조심하세요
What
무엇
Yun Yang, be careful
윤양아, 조심해
as a sister
자매로서
You said this when you first met me
당신은 나를 처음 만났을 때 이렇게 말했어요.
looks dangerous
위험해 보여
When you look at a goal and move forward
목표를 바라보고 앞으로 나아갈 때
This is a common trap
이건 흔한 함정이야
How are you?
어떻게 지내세요?
That's why you have to be careful
그렇기 때문에 조심해야 해요
let's get into consciousness
의식에 들어가자
drink slowly
천천히 마시다
this is gonna be really crazy
이건 정말 미친 짓이 될 거야
Don't look at it like that
그렇게 보지 마세요
This is not a dangerous place in our house.
우리 집은 위험한 곳이 아니다 .
It's just that the method is wrong
다만 방법이 잘못됐을 뿐이죠
This is not ordinary
이건 보통이 아니야
Let's have a drink and enjoy
한잔 마시고 즐기자
I like you
좋아해요
Do you know this, Wu Guang?
이거 알아요, 우광?
I can't say, but I can know
말할 수는 없지만 알 수는 있어요
Maybe you just pretend not to know
어쩌면 넌 그냥 모른 척하고 있을지도 몰라
This means it's not the first time
이번이 처음이 아니라는 뜻이다
It means it will be fine soon
곧 괜찮아질 거라는 뜻이에요
Mother
어머니
This is a sad picture
슬픈 사진이네요
will be very convenient
매우 편리할 것입니다
Who are you looking for?
당신은 누구를 찾고 있나요?
This guy
이 남자
How are you?
어떻게 지내세요?
Come
오다
Did you tell me to trust you ?
나한테 널 믿으라고 했지 ?
please
제발
not really
설마
I am strong
나는 강하다
Please trust me
제발 날 믿어
Then let's meet in Wuzhengli
그럼 Wuzhengli에서 만나요
Because I'll tell you what it means
왜냐면 그게 무슨 뜻인지 말해줄 테니까
keep living and hold on
계속 살아가고 버텨라
I'm afraid he won't come
그 사람이 안 올까 봐 걱정돼요
I'm still worried that I won't be able to come
아직도 못 올까봐 걱정돼
listen carefully
잘 들어
From now on your life will be absolute hell
이제부터 네 인생은 완전 지옥이 될 거야
I never took my eyes off you for a moment
한 순간도 너에게서 눈을 떼지 않았어
Because I will watch until the end
끝까지 지켜볼 테니까
If you have debt to pay
갚아야 할 빚이 있는 경우
no matter what
무슨 일이 있어도
I'll make sure you don't miss a single payment
단 한 번의 결제도 놓치지 않도록 할게요
That's why it must be really good
그러니까 정말 좋아야지
Prisoner number 4013
죄수 번호 4013
Wuminsu
우민수
Who are you?
누구세요?
a little hair
약간의 머리카락
How did you know I'd be there?
내가 거기 있을 줄 어떻게 알았어?
Because I think it's my turn
이제 내 차례인 것 같으니까
List of main suspects at the time
당시 주요 용의자 명단
There are three people including you.
당신을 포함해 세 사람이 있어요.
(1987 murder suspect Ba Xixiu)
(1987년 살인 용의자 바시시우)
The murder that will happen in three days
사흘 안에 일어날 살인 사건
The first suspect is Pakistan
첫 번째 용의자는 파키스탄이다.
The second suspect is Yu Bum Yong
두 번째 용의자는 유범용이다.
(Bom Bom Theater)
(봄봄극장)
(Judaism)
(유태교)
A third suspect has been identified as the culprit
세 번째 용의자가 범인으로 확인됐다.
Thirty years in prison
감옥에서 30년
Wuminsu
우민수
(Wu Minsu)
(우민수)
Isn't that the person you met today?
오늘 만난 사람이 그 사람 아닌가요?
(Bom Bom Theater)
(봄봄극장)
Who are you?
누구세요?
Why are you really here?
진짜 왜 여기 있는 거야?
"A Stranger I Met"
"내가 만난 낯선 사람"
Two days before the first case appeared
첫 사례가 나타나기 이틀 전
one of the suspects
용의자 중 한 명
He has been arrested at the police station
그는 경찰서에서 체포됐다.
The other two are still inconspicuous
나머지 두 개는 아직 눈에 띄지 않네요
Everything was covered in fog then
그땐 모든 게 안개로 뒤덮였지
She is coming
그녀가오고있다
she is the first victim
그 사람이 첫번째 피해자야
that person..
저 사람..
i know something
나 뭔가 알아
If you don't know what happens here
여기서 무슨 일이 일어나는지 모른다면
must be informed
알려야 한다
Because we don't know what will happen in the future
우리는 앞으로 무슨 일이 일어날지 모르기 때문에
(appendix)
(부록)
"A Stranger I Met"
"내가 만난 낯선 사람"